<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Ryan Wang</title>
    <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/media/icon_hu9929750aa6c345baea2685e82ac1c0be_431545_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from the neighbors: The diffusion of state broadband policies in United States</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project will examine how state broadband policies diffused among the states in the United States over the last 30-year period utilizing a network approach and a recently released dataset, the State Broadband Explorer curated by the Pew Charitable Trusts’s Broadband Initiates (2019). The 835 state broadband policies in the United States (until January 2021) have been categorized into six main themes: broadband programs, competition and regulation, definitions, funding and financing, infrastructure access and legislative intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigate broadband policies diffusion in the United States at the state level. The existing policy literature has identified four types of diffusion mechanisms: (1) learning by the success (or failure) of policies in other adopting units; (2) competition with other geographical units (i.e., states) for resources; (3) conformity to mandates from higher jurisdictions (such as national governments or international organizations); and (4) emulation of other units perceived to be ideologically compatible. Drawing from the broader policy diffusion literature, the current study aims at presenting the very first examination of state broadband policy diffusion in the United States with a network approach. Specifically, we examine in which states are emerging as exemplars in specific thematic areas and what mechanisms are at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of employing the traditional approach of event history analysis in policy diffusion literature, this study adopts a network approach based on recent methodological developments. Our purposes in the present study are two-fold: (1) utilizing the netinf algorithm (Gomez-Rodriguez et al., 2012), we infer a latent network of broadband policy diffusion in the United States for the past 30 years. Simultaneously, it uses the centrality measure and community detection algorithm to identify the facilitators (and early adopters) of the diffusion. (2) Building on the latent network generated from the first part, we test the determinants of the observed patterns of diffusion with a multilevel and dynamic logistic model (with pairs of states as the unit of analysis). Specifically, the logistic model incorporates the nodal-level state characteristics including social-demographic factors (i.e., population), political and legislative factors (i.e., legislative control, state governors’ party, state political partisanship), economic factors (i.e., state GDP), as well as the geographical factors such as geographical proximity and contiguity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-temporal analysis of broadband penetration in the United States: An INLA approach</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/broadband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/broadband/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this study, we are using the current standard of fixed broadband as 25 megabits per second for downloads (Mpbs) and 3 Mpbs for uploads, as defined by the Federal Communication Committees in 2015 and provided through Form 477. Albeit the criticism on the Form 477 data, it is still the most granular data source in terms of its spatial and temporal availability.We are adopting the bottom-up aggregation approach from the census tract level to the county level (N = 3,108 contiguous U.S. counties), in order to better reduce the potential bias led by self-filed broadband metrics collected on a higher order of geographies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytically, we are using the Bayesian spatio-temporal statistic model in this project, which is specified with Integrated Nested Laplace Approximation. The biggest advantage of Bayesian inference with an INLA approach is its flexibility to incorporate the latent spatial (i.e., Besag-York-Mollié model) and temporal effects (i.e., random-walk model), and also a space-time interaction. Additionally, it is more efficient when compared to other computationally intensive models such as the Markov Chain Monte Carlo algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sum, this paper aims at identifying the spatial patterns of broadband penetration in the U.S. and how these patterns evolve over the period of 2016-2020. In particular, we would like to examine the spatial heterogeneity and dependence of broadband penetration in a broader context of (spatial) digital inequality. Such polarized and inequal patterns could lead to further consequences in economic development, community building, and political participation, within various spatial regimes. This paper could further contribute to the literature as the first study on the U.S.’s broadband penetration while taking the spatial, temporal, and their interaction effects into account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trump effect on &#34;Chinese virus&#34;: Did Trump fuel the toxicity in the Twitterverse?</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/trump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/trump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Along with the controversy amidst the public health crisis of COVID-19 pandemic, racist harassment, physical violent attacks, and even vandalism targeting Asians and people of Asian descent have spiked in the wake of the pandemic. Among all the cases, the tweet using ‘Chinese virus’ posted by U.S. then-president &lt;em&gt;Donald J. Trump&lt;/em&gt; on March 16th, 2020 was one of the most controversial spices intensified the public sphere, even though he claimed to stop using the term during an interview with Fox News on March 24th. Amid an uptick in anti-Asian violence, Trump’s incendiary rhetoric has been singled out as particularly damaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts and policy makers have warned against using inflammatory and racist tweets since they can serve as a rallying cry for hate crimes. The expressions of ‘Chinese virus’ personify the threat and associate the infection with an ethnicity. This type of language stokes anxiety, resentment, fear and disgust toward people associated with that group. Previous study has recognized the Trump effect — Trump’s racially discrimination language emboldened individuals to voice their prejudice and to act on them (Newman et al., 2020). Such an effect allows us to argue that Trump’s ‘Chinese virus’ tweet may escalate hate speech not only on social media but also in real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we aim to explore the public expression of toxicity online after Trump’s tweet, denoted as the &lt;em&gt;Trump effect&lt;/em&gt;. We are particularly interested in whether the Trump effect has escalated the volume of toxicity in the Twitterverse and whether there is a lasting effect following Trump’s tweet. Using non-linear interrupted time series analysis, we have detected a significant and positive &lt;em&gt;Trump effect&lt;/em&gt; on the hourly volume of toxicity on our &amp;lsquo;Chinese virus&amp;rsquo; corpus of 300,550 tweets during a short frame of time, but only in three types of toxicity: severe toxicity, threat and identity attack, as classified by BERT using a pre-trained model. And after incoporating temporal autocorrelation, the resulsts still hold as further confirmed by the ARIMA models.Only threat detects a lasting rise caused by Trump effect, as indicated by the positive shift instantly following Trump’s tweet, and the positive post-treatment slope change. The joint effect of the quadratics terms only worked for severe toxicity, which is slowly progressively increase over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation as anti-propaganda weapon? An exploratory analysis of #TheGreatTranslationMovement on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/tgtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/tgtm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chinese Communist Party, with its massive propaganda machine, has been disseminating pro-Russia and pro-Putin narrative to Chinese public even before the Russian invasion of Ukraine starting in late February 2022, due to their “no limit” partnership. Alongside the development of China’s aggressive diplomatic voice (the &amp;ldquo;wolf warrior&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot;), and nationalistic public opinion (the &amp;ldquo;little pink&amp;rdquo;) towards the United States and its ally, the majority of radical opinion climate in China towards the Russian invasion of Ukraine has mainly sided with Putin. Meanwhile, Chinese censorship has also effectively silenced the expression for the camp of pro-Ukraine or against the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocked by the Great Firewall, Chinese public has been isolated from outside information. And because of the language barrier, non-Chinese languages users are hard to access the public opinion formation within Chinese media environment. Since March 8th, 2022, a group of Chinese Internet anonymous dissents has started a decentralized &lt;em&gt;The Great Translation Movement&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TGTM_Official&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@TGTM_Official&lt;/a&gt;), which aims at translating not just the pro-war messages promoted by Chinese state-affiliated media, but also the radical and hateful speech from the Putin supporters across Chinese social media platforms, from Chinese to multiple languages – or rather, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://thediplomat.com/2022/04/the-great-translation-movement-shines-a-spotlight-on-chinas-propaganda/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Diplomat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; called, &amp;ldquo;the dark side of the Chinese internet&amp;rdquo; against Chinese president Xi Jinping’s &amp;ldquo;Telling China’s Story Well&amp;rdquo;. Additionally, by utilizing the hashtag #TheGreatTranslationMovement, the dissents also advocated for translation via crowdsourced efforts on Twitter. Since the online movement has extended the content beyond the Russia-Ukraine war, which include but not limited to COVID-19 pandemic, anti-US or anti-Japan sentiment, and etc. Nonetheless, the online movement is also facing some critics as translating and spreading hate speech might ignite the anti-Chinese sentiment, which might be led to the anti-Asian hate crime in countries like United States and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims at providing an exploratory analysis of &lt;em&gt;#TheGreatTranslationMovement&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter. Since this is an ongoing data collection process, the preliminary analysis plans to focus on the English tweets with the hashtag #TheGreatTranslationMovement, via Twitter’s API 2.0 for Academic Research. The main goal for the exploratory analysis is two-folded: (1) what content has been translated in the movement so far; and (2) who on Twitter are participating in the movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spatial Inequality of Connectivity: a Spatial Analysis of Public Wi-Fi Locations in New York City</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/wifi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project offers the very first examination of the spatial patterns of public Wi-Fi hotspots deployment in New York City. Furthermore, it utilizes the Spatially Aware Technology Utilization Model to investigate what drivers (i.e. demographic and socio-economic factors, digital infrastructure, and political affiliation) might impact the spatial distribution of public Wi-Fi hotspot deployment with Geographically Weighted Regression. Through the hot spot analysis, we find that the deployment of public Wi-Fi hotspots is not spatially equal across the five boroughs of New York City. Instead, it is highly clustered in Manhattan as the “hot spot”, while there are a few “cold spots” identified in the other four boroughs. We also find that the deployment of public Wi-Fi hotspots does not favor African American communities, economically depressed neighborhoods, or Republican supporters (compared to Democrats supporters). Meanwhile, none of the digital infrastructure factors play a significant role here. The findings show that the public Wi-Fi hotspots deployment under Internet Master Plan by the de Blasio administration actually reinforces existing gaps in broadband infrastructures, and it does not mitigate broadband access disparities between digitally marginalized areas and the rest of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
