<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Social Science | Ryan Wang</title>
    <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/tag/computational-social-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ryanyangwang.github.io/tag/computational-social-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computational Social Science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/media/icon_hu9929750aa6c345baea2685e82ac1c0be_431545_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Computational Social Science</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/tag/computational-social-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trump effect on &#34;Chinese virus&#34;: Did Trump fuel the toxicity in the Twitterverse?</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/trump/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/trump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Along with the controversy amidst the public health crisis of COVID-19 pandemic, racist harassment, physical violent attacks, and even vandalism targeting Asians and people of Asian descent have spiked in the wake of the pandemic. Among all the cases, the tweet using ‘Chinese virus’ posted by U.S. then-president &lt;em&gt;Donald J. Trump&lt;/em&gt; on March 16th, 2020 was one of the most controversial spices intensified the public sphere, even though he claimed to stop using the term during an interview with Fox News on March 24th. Amid an uptick in anti-Asian violence, Trump’s incendiary rhetoric has been singled out as particularly damaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts and policy makers have warned against using inflammatory and racist tweets since they can serve as a rallying cry for hate crimes. The expressions of ‘Chinese virus’ personify the threat and associate the infection with an ethnicity. This type of language stokes anxiety, resentment, fear and disgust toward people associated with that group. Previous study has recognized the Trump effect — Trump’s racially discrimination language emboldened individuals to voice their prejudice and to act on them (Newman et al., 2020). Such an effect allows us to argue that Trump’s ‘Chinese virus’ tweet may escalate hate speech not only on social media but also in real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we aim to explore the public expression of toxicity online after Trump’s tweet, denoted as the &lt;em&gt;Trump effect&lt;/em&gt;. We are particularly interested in whether the Trump effect has escalated the volume of toxicity in the Twitterverse and whether there is a lasting effect following Trump’s tweet. Using non-linear interrupted time series analysis, we have detected a significant and positive &lt;em&gt;Trump effect&lt;/em&gt; on the hourly volume of toxicity on our &amp;lsquo;Chinese virus&amp;rsquo; corpus of 300,550 tweets during a short frame of time, but only in three types of toxicity: severe toxicity, threat and identity attack, as classified by BERT using a pre-trained model. And after incoporating temporal autocorrelation, the resulsts still hold as further confirmed by the ARIMA models.Only threat detects a lasting rise caused by Trump effect, as indicated by the positive shift instantly following Trump’s tweet, and the positive post-treatment slope change. The joint effect of the quadratics terms only worked for severe toxicity, which is slowly progressively increase over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation as anti-propaganda weapon? An exploratory analysis of #TheGreatTranslationMovement on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/tgtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanyangwang.github.io/project/tgtm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chinese Communist Party, with its massive propaganda machine, has been disseminating pro-Russia and pro-Putin narrative to Chinese public even before the Russian invasion of Ukraine starting in late February 2022, due to their “no limit” partnership. Alongside the development of China’s aggressive diplomatic voice (the &amp;ldquo;wolf warrior&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot;), and nationalistic public opinion (the &amp;ldquo;little pink&amp;rdquo;) towards the United States and its ally, the majority of radical opinion climate in China towards the Russian invasion of Ukraine has mainly sided with Putin. Meanwhile, Chinese censorship has also effectively silenced the expression for the camp of pro-Ukraine or against the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocked by the Great Firewall, Chinese public has been isolated from outside information. And because of the language barrier, non-Chinese languages users are hard to access the public opinion formation within Chinese media environment. Since March 8th, 2022, a group of Chinese Internet anonymous dissents has started a decentralized &lt;em&gt;The Great Translation Movement&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TGTM_Official&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@TGTM_Official&lt;/a&gt;), which aims at translating not just the pro-war messages promoted by Chinese state-affiliated media, but also the radical and hateful speech from the Putin supporters across Chinese social media platforms, from Chinese to multiple languages – or rather, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://thediplomat.com/2022/04/the-great-translation-movement-shines-a-spotlight-on-chinas-propaganda/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Diplomat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; called, &amp;ldquo;the dark side of the Chinese internet&amp;rdquo; against Chinese president Xi Jinping’s &amp;ldquo;Telling China’s Story Well&amp;rdquo;. Additionally, by utilizing the hashtag #TheGreatTranslationMovement, the dissents also advocated for translation via crowdsourced efforts on Twitter. Since the online movement has extended the content beyond the Russia-Ukraine war, which include but not limited to COVID-19 pandemic, anti-US or anti-Japan sentiment, and etc. Nonetheless, the online movement is also facing some critics as translating and spreading hate speech might ignite the anti-Chinese sentiment, which might be led to the anti-Asian hate crime in countries like United States and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims at providing an exploratory analysis of &lt;em&gt;#TheGreatTranslationMovement&lt;/em&gt; on Twitter. Since this is an ongoing data collection process, the preliminary analysis plans to focus on the English tweets with the hashtag #TheGreatTranslationMovement, via Twitter’s API 2.0 for Academic Research. The main goal for the exploratory analysis is two-folded: (1) what content has been translated in the movement so far; and (2) who on Twitter are participating in the movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
